<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://susanjsp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://susanjsp.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-03T00:27:36+10:00</updated><id>http://susanjsp.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Susan Pan</title><subtitle>I created this blog to document my career journey from Pharmacist to Software Engineering. I hope to solidify my learning and to also develop my written communication skills through writing technical posts about web development.</subtitle><author><name>Susan Pan</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome 2021!</title><link href="http://susanjsp.com/personal/2021/01/02/happy-new-year-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome 2021!" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://susanjsp.com/personal/2021/01/02/happy-new-year-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://susanjsp.com/personal/2021/01/02/happy-new-year-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy new year!! It’s finally 2021, and it could not have come any sooner. I think I can confidently speak for all of us when I say 2020 was a bit of a sht-show. &lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not to worry, there’s a new year ahead of us where we’ll all accomplish great things!! To everyone who is reading, studying, hustling or building projects to become a better developer, this year will bring great success. Whether you are looking to create a start-up, or to finally land that first developer role that you’ve wanted, this will be the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been really bad at setting new years’ resolutions - I’d worry so much about what I’d wear to NYE events that I’d forget about the coming year. This will be the year that I start. It’s as good a time as any to do a bit of self-reflection and think about what we want to achieve and why.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Susan Pan</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Happy new year!! It’s finally 2021, and it could not have come any sooner. I think I can confidently speak for all of us when I say 2020 was a bit of a sht-show.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first blog post!</title><link href="http://susanjsp.com/personal%20development/2020/12/30/my-first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first blog post!" /><published>2020-12-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-12-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://susanjsp.com/personal%20development/2020/12/30/my-first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://susanjsp.com/personal%20development/2020/12/30/my-first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I’ve created this so that I have my own corner of the internet to write about all the things I’ve learnt about tech. &lt;!--break--&gt;
I’m hoping to use this platform as a way for me to really bring home the core software engineering concepts while also practising my written communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the posts I create will be to document my progress on side-projects, my career journey or technical posts for new concepts that I come across. Although I’m only at the very beginning of my tech career, I hope there will be some things that you can learn from my posts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read this! Feel free to stay and have a little poke around, but don’t forget to take a break and have a quick stretch before you continue :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Susan Pan</name></author><category term="personal development" /><category term="personal" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html">Welcome to my blog! I’ve created this so that I have my own corner of the internet to write about all the things I’ve learnt about tech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating my first blog with Jekyll</title><link href="http://susanjsp.com/jekyll/2020/12/26/creating-blog-with-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating my first blog with Jekyll" /><published>2020-12-26T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-12-26T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://susanjsp.com/jekyll/2020/12/26/creating-blog-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://susanjsp.com/jekyll/2020/12/26/creating-blog-with-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a framework that makes creating static websites super simple. A static website is one where there isn’t too much server-side programming. &lt;!--break--&gt;These types of websites don’t need the in-depth, extensive network of heavier frameworks such as Ruby on Rails. Some examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company websites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-sites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educational websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I jumped from Rails to Jekyll, the installation and syntax was relatively straight-forward, I didn’t bump into any obstacles until I tried using some of the jekyll gems - but more on that later. If you’re just beginning, the Jekyll documentation is superb. Everything is explained well with great examples to follow. If you get stuck, look there first!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Susan Pan</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="coding" /><summary type="html">Jekyll is a framework that makes creating static websites super simple. A static website is one where there isn’t too much server-side programming.</summary></entry></feed>